<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Smart Mobility Lab Students</title>
    <description>Long Form Jekyll theme built with SASS</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 08:47:53 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 08:47:53 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.2</generator><item>
        <title>Fabrice Sindambiwe: My summer internship at KABISA Electric Ltd</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/kabisa-event.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;70%&quot; style=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Fabrice Sindambiwe&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Fabrice Sindambiwe at a Kabisa event&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This summer, I had the incredible opportunity to intern at KABISA Electric Ltd., a leading electric vehicle distributor and EV ecosystem company in Rwanda. KABISA’s mission to simplify electric vehicle adoption and ownership in Rwanda aligns perfectly with my passion for renewable energy and sustainable technologies. As a Charging Infrastructure Engineer, I was involved in various tasks, including site visits for potential charger installations, installing chargers at different levels, participating in after-sales operations, and educating EV users on charging schemes. The experience allowed me to work hands-on with a cutting-edge EV charging network and to see the real-life application of e-mobility solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/kabisa-team.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;80%&quot; style=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Fabrice Sindambiwe&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Fabrice Sindambiwe and the Kabisa team&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout my internship, I was fortunate to contribute to several key projects, such as installing chargers at Viebeg Warehouse, SAWA Citi Supermarket, IREMBO Campus, and SOLID Africa, among other locations. A highlight was participating in the setup of a 240kW Supercharger at SP KANOMBE I and expanding the charging network across 15 SP Stations. My final contribution before resuming my studies was leading the installation of three Level 2 Chargers at SP NYAMATA, SP MUHANGA, and SP RWAMAGANA. These projects not only deepened my technical knowledge but also gave me valuable insights into the growing field of e-mobility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;div style=&quot;display:flex;&quot;&gt; --&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;div style=&quot;display:flex;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/KABs.bmp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; style=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Fabrice Sindambiwe&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/Kbas.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;40%&quot; style=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Fabrice Sindambiwe&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;figcaption&gt;Fabrice Sindambiwe at work!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/KABs.bmp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;70%&quot; style=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Fabrice Sindambiwe&quot;&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Fabrice Sindambiwe at work!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt; --&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;/div&gt; --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with the KABISA team was an enriching experience, both professionally and personally. I had the pleasure of collaborating with a talented and joyful group of professionals, forming lasting friendships with colleagues like Lukas, Ryan, Lim, Winston, Alex, Mary, Iliiza, Nick Hu, Marumbo, Remy, Rodrigue, David, and others. The internship concluded with a memorable retreat at UMVA MUHAZI, which was a perfect way to celebrate our accomplishments. I’m truly grateful for this opportunity and look forward to the possibility of working with the KABISA team again in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><description>&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/kabisa-event.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;70%&quot; style=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Fabrice Sindambiwe&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Fabrice Sindambiwe at a Kabisa event&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/fabrice-sindambiwe-work-highlights/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/fabrice-sindambiwe-work-highlights/</guid></item><item>
        <title>Abdul Jalil Zakaria: Work Highlights</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My work at GIZ over the past months has been an enriching experience, marked by both learning
and applying new skills to impactful projects. I developed a concept note for a capacity needs
assessment aimed at evaluating government institutions’ readiness to support the drive of electric
mobility in Rwanda. This project is critical in identifying institutional gaps and proposing tailored
capacity-building initiatives to advance electric mobility in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/abdulprofile.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; style=&quot;margin-left:25%;&quot; title=&quot;Abdul Jalil Zakaria&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Abdul Jalil Zakaria&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am particularly excited about the upcoming field survey, where I will analyze the findings and
engage with various stakeholders in Rwanda’s transport ecosystem, further enhancing my
stakeholder engagement skills. These experiences are invaluable to my career development, paving
the way for me to become a policy analyst and thought leader in the energy, transport, and
technology sectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am deeply grateful to my supervisors, Mateo Gomez, and Francois Zirikana for their unwavering
support and the learning opportunities they have provided thus far.&lt;/p&gt;

</description><description>&lt;p&gt;My work at GIZ over the past months has been an enriching experience, marked by both learning
and applying new skills to impactful projects. I developed a concept note for a capacity needs
assessment aimed at evaluating government institutions’ readiness to support the drive of electric
mobility in Rwanda. This project is critical in identifying institutional gaps and proposing tailored
capacity-building initiatives to advance electric mobility in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/abdul-Jalil-work-highlights/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/abdul-Jalil-work-highlights/</guid></item><item>
        <title>David Tuyishimire Neza</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am excited to share my progress as an intern at the Smart Mobility Lab and Volkswagen Mobility Solutions Rwanda. I have had a great experience with Serge and his team, who have been instrumental in helping me achieve my goals and succeed in my work. Their feedback and support have been invaluable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/David-vw.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;60%&quot; style=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;David Tuyishimire Neza&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;David Tuyishimire Neza&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently working on a driver profiling platform/system, which will be crucial in understanding the different metrics contributing to a driver’s efficiency and success. This platform will help Volkswagen Mobility Solutions Rwanda’s ride-hailing service “Move” continue to provide world-class services to its customers. By leveraging data science and technology, we can significantly improve the quality of services we offer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><description>&lt;p&gt;I am excited to share my progress as an intern at the Smart Mobility Lab and Volkswagen Mobility Solutions Rwanda. I have had a great experience with Serge and his team, who have been instrumental in helping me achieve my goals and succeed in my work. Their feedback and support have been invaluable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/david-neza-vw/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/david-neza-vw/</guid></item><item>
        <title>Chryssie Karera: My internship experience at VWSR</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/chryssieprofile.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Chryssie Karera&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Chryssie Karera&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Chryssie Karera, a graduate student at CMU Africa, currently interning at Volkswagen
Mobility Solutions Rwanda as part of the Carnegie Mellon University Africa summer internship
program. I would like to share insights and updates on how my internship has gone so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Projects and Tasks&lt;/strong&gt;: As a data analyst at VWSR, my main job is to work with data. My initial tasks
involved collecting data from different VWSR departments and transforming it into visual
representations to help the company understand its performance more easily. This was challenging
because of the large volume of data, and I had to identify the most meaningful indicators. This
required working closely with representatives from various departments to find the best metrics.
One significant analysis I conducted was identifying hotspot areas for ride-hailing services, breaking
it down by weekdays, hourly demand, and monthly trip numbers and averages. Additionally, I
collaborated with departments that have daily operations to automate their data collection
processes, which are now successfully in use. This task was complex as it involved understanding
their requirements thoroughly and ensuring that key performance indicators could be easily
measured with the new system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skills and Technologies&lt;/strong&gt;: Throughout my work, I had to find the best technologies to accomplish my
tasks. My skills in exploratory data analysis have significantly improved, especially as I worked with
various departments to meet their needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Challenges&lt;/strong&gt;: Every job comes with its challenges, and mine was no different. One of the main
challenges was aggregating data from different sources and finding a representation solution that
worked for all. Through persistence and experimentation, I eventually found a solution that was
well-received by the VWSR team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Memorable Experience&lt;/strong&gt;: A memorable experience was presenting my work to the senior
management at VWSR after two months. The presentation was well-received and is now guiding the
team in implementing visual analytics solutions. Seeing the data collection solution I developed
being used in their daily operations boosted my confidence and demonstrated the impact of my
internship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Career Goals&lt;/strong&gt;: This internship has been crucial in shaping my career goals. It provided me with
practical experience in applying data analysis skills learned at CMU and gave me exposure to working
with a leading organization in the transport sector, both in Rwanda and worldwide. Although I never
thought I would work in the transport sector, this experience has been incredibly motivating and has
inspired me to pursue a career in data analysis, aiming to contribute to decision-making and the
advancement of solutions using data as the main focus.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><description>&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/chryssieprofile.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Chryssie Karera&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Chryssie Karera&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/chryssie-karera-vw/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/chryssie-karera-vw/</guid></item><item>
        <title>Abdul Jalil Zakaria at GIZ Rwanda</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Abdul is an alumnus of the CMU-Africa Class of 2024 within the MS-ECE Program. He works as a consultant with the Climate, Energy, and Sustainable Urban Development Cluster of GIZ Rwanda, contributing to various electric mobility project components. These projects aim to support the Rwandan government in electrifying public transport fleets in secondary/satellite cities and intercity transport, as well as promoting the electrification of the transport sector in Rwanda through capacity building and awareness raising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/abdulprofile.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; style=&quot;margin-left:25%;&quot; title=&quot;Abdul Jalil Zakaria&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Abdul Jalil Zakaria&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His current responsibilities include supporting the development of a policy paper on minibus electrification, conducting research on capacity needs assessment for public transport electrification, and developing a concept for EV maintenance training for the private sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abdul is thrilled to be part of the GIZ Mobility Team, working towards making mobility more sustainable and contributing to the transformation of the transport sector in Rwanda.&lt;/p&gt;

</description><description>&lt;p&gt;Abdul is an alumnus of the CMU-Africa Class of 2024 within the MS-ECE Program. He works as a consultant with the Climate, Energy, and Sustainable Urban Development Cluster of GIZ Rwanda, contributing to various electric mobility project components. These projects aim to support the Rwandan government in electrifying public transport fleets in secondary/satellite cities and intercity transport, as well as promoting the electrification of the transport sector in Rwanda through capacity building and awareness raising.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/abdul-Jalil-giz/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/abdul-Jalil-giz/</guid></item><item>
        <title>Fabrice Sindambiwe at Kabisa</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Fabrice Sindambiwe is currently a Charging Infrastructure intern at Kabisa, an e-mobility company providing electric vehicle services in Africa. Below are the daily tasks Fabrice is involved in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conducting electric vehicle charger installations, either personally or by coordinating with contractors hired by Kabisa.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Performing maintenance and troubleshooting in emergency situations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Addressing customer requests regarding charger malfunctions, faults, or other issues.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conducting site visits to perform feasibility studies for potential charger installations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Converting various types of chargers with different power connectors to the Schuko model, which is common in Africa.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Participating in project planning related to Kabisa’s charging activities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description><description>&lt;p&gt;Fabrice Sindambiwe is currently a Charging Infrastructure intern at Kabisa, an e-mobility company providing electric vehicle services in Africa. Below are the daily tasks Fabrice is involved in:&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/Fabrice-Sindambiwe-post/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/Fabrice-Sindambiwe-post/</guid></item></channel>
</rss>
